grandecom.com 2009-12-31

# Grande Communications - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Statement

Grande Communications Holdings, Inc. and its subsidiary, Grande Communications Networks, Inc. (collectively, "Grande Communications"), have created this privacy statement outlining your privacy rights in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the websites operated by Grande Communications which can be found at Grandecom.com and Grandecom.net (collectively, the 'Site'). You can read our policy with respect to Children's Privacy by clicking here.

Grande Communications is the sole owner of the information collected on the Site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. Grande Communications collects information from our users at several different points on our Site as further described in this statement.

The following links are made available to help you find what you are looking for in our Privacy Statement:

  * How And When We Collect Information 
  * How We Use Your Information 
  * California Privacy Rights 
  * Abuse of Appropriate Use Policy 
  * Law Enforcement 
  * Cookies
  * Linked Sites 
  * Choice/Opt-Out 
  * How We Use Email 
  * Security
  * Changes to Privacy Statement 
  * Policy regarding Children's Use of Site
  * Implementation of Children's Privacy Statement 
  * Changes to Children's Privacy Statement   

####  How And When We Collect Information

We collect 'personal' information from you when you provide it to us. When you access our Site, we automatically collect access log information about your visit, including information such as the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses assigned (numbers assigned to your computer while online), bandwidth used, system and connection performance, browsers used, dates and times of access, and Internet resource requests, including requests to access web pages. If you purchase cable, phone, internet, or security monitoring services ("Services") from us, we may collect your name, mailing address, drivers license number, social security number, telephone number, credit card number and email address, certain additional information as provided in our Residential Agreement, and online traffic, actions and anonymous surfing data (in general, "click-stream data") and data which can be used to provide a better online experience. 

If you contact us, we may collect your email address and the content of your communications. If you utilize services or take advantage of special offers made by us or our marketing partners, we may collect other personal information about you. If you transmit a service inquiry, we may collect information about your usage of our services regardless of whether the services utilized consist of cable, phone, internet, or security monitoring services.

Grande Communications collects information online by asking you for it, for example, to order a service, apply for a job, or in responding to your email. Grande Communications may also use 'cookies' and similar technology to obtain information about your visits to our Site in an aggregated data format that does not identify you. These tools tell us the parts of our Site or emails, which we sent, caused you to take some action and help us improve the quality and usefulness of our Site.

Grande Communications collects information we deem necessary to provide services to you and to comply with applicable governmental regulations and requests.

####  How We Use Your Information

We collect, store, and process your personal information on servers located in the United States. We use the information we collect about you in order (1) to provide our services and process your transactions, (2) to provide customer service, (3) to determine your eligibility to receive offers for special features or products, (4) to improve our products and services, (5) to comply with governmental regulations and requests, (6) to deal with fraud and unauthorized use of our Services. Additionally, we share your information with our parent company, subsidiaries and joint ventures to help coordinate the services we provide to you, enforce our appropriate use policy, and promote trust and safety. 

Unless addressed to us, we do not read email messages, instant messages, online chats, or the content of other online communications that reside on or pass through our Services. We may, however, retain and provide such communications if we are legally required to do so or for one of the purposes set forth above. Incoming and outgoing email messages are generally scanned electronically to identify and filter out likely spam and for viruses and related problems that could harm your equipment, the network, or other users.

As with any other business, it is possible that Grande Communications in the future could merge with another company or Grande Communications or its assets or one or more of its business lines could be acquired by another company. If such an acquisition occurs, the successor company would have access to the information maintained by Grande Communications, including customer account information, but would continue to be bound by this Privacy Statement unless and until it is amended as described below. 

Grande Communications will not sell or rent any of your personally identifiable information to third parties. Grande Communications will share your personally identifiable information with third parties that are its suppliers, affiliates or business partners of Grande Communications in order to provide Grande Communications services to you or to provide you with notification of those services. These third parties are limited by law or by contract from using the information for secondary purposes beyond the purposes for which the information is shared. Grande Communications will not share any of your personally identifiable information with third parties other than its suppliers, affiliates, or business partners except with your express permission. 

#### California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident and Grande Communications has an established business relationship with you, you have the right to request information from Grande Communications regarding the manner in which Grande Communications shares certain categories of your personal information with third parties (whether collected online or offline) for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. California law provides that you have the right to submit a request to Grande Communications at its designated address and receive the following information: (1) the categories of information Grande Communications disclosed to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year; (2) the names and addresses of third parties that received such information; and (3) if the nature of a third party's business cannot be reasonably determined from the third party's name, examples of the products or services marketed. You are entitled to receive a copy of this information in a standardized format and the information will not be specific to you individually. For purposes of this paragraph: 'Grande Communications' means Grande Communications and the Site, and 'Third Party' means a business that is outside the Grande Communications family of companies. Grande Communications' designated email address for such requests is [legal@grandecom.com](mailto:legal@grandecom.com). You may also request this information by writing to: Legal Department, Grande Communications Networks, Inc., 401 Carlson Circle, San Marcos, Texas 78666. 

####  Abuse of Appropriate Use Policy

We have the right to share your name and contact information with our attorneys and law enforcement officials, if needed, in the event we believe you have breached our Appropriate Use Policy or otherwise harmed us or any of our customers in any way.

#### Law Enforcement

Legal Requirements: - As a provider of Internet communications services, we regularly receive legal requests for customer information from government and law enforcement personnel. We also receive discovery requests in civil litigation. In all such cases, our policy is to cooperate as required by law, but to provide only such information as the law requires. This information is generally sought by subpoena served on Grande Communications. Under current law, many criminal subpoenas require that we not disclose or notify you of the request. Due to this fact and the volume of requests we receive, we cannot assume any duty to notify you of receipt of any legal requests. 

Internet Information: Current law provides that personal account and other information concerning use of our internet services may be subpoenaed by governmental entities. In such cases, you may not be entitled to notice of such a request. The content of internet communications may not generally be sought through use of a subpoena. The law does permit us to disclose to law enforcement, voluntarily and without prior notice, customer information, including the contents of communications, if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury requires such disclosure without delay. 

Telephone Information: In some areas, Grande Communications provides telephone services to its customers. Current law requires law enforcement to obtain a court order or warrant for a telephone wiretap or to use a pen register or trap and trace device to capture dialing information. 

####  Cookies

A cookie is a small data file that certain websites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the website uses to track the pages you have visited. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. The information stored by one website into a cookie cannot be read by another website.

We use cookies to provide you a richer, personalized experience on our Site, to customize your shopping experience, and to remember who you are when you revisit our Site. Additionally, if you have chosen to Opt Out of certain communications, you must accept cookies. We do not store any personal information about you in the cookie. We also use this ID to track the pages you visit on our Site. 

####  Linked Sites

Our Site may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that Grande Communications is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Grande Communications.

####  Choice/Opt-Out

Our Site provides you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us. Grande Communications gives you the following options for removing your information from our database so that you do not receive future communications:

#### You can visit the Contact Us section on our Site. 

You can call the following telephone number and ask to be removed from future mailings: 512.878.4600. 

By following the above outlined cost-free procedure, you may prevent certain disclosures of personal information.

####  How We Use Email

Occasionally, we send out email updates on products, services, sales, special events, and promotions. Customers whom we think might be interested in learning about this information will receive these emails. 

We also use email as a means of communicating with our customers. We love to hear from you, and we encourage you to email us with your questions or comments.

Grande Communications provides customers with a means of declining email offers. Although most customers tell us they appreciate receiving notice of these opportunities, we recognize the importance of providing you with choices. Email offers that you receive from Grande Communications will tell you how to decline further email offers. At any time, you may request to discontinue receiving these offers from us by simply following the instructions contained in the email about how to inform us of your preferences.

####  Security

We use encryption, firewalls, and other technology and security procedures to help protect the accuracy and security of your personal information and prevent unauthorized access or improper use. For example, you will note that the online payments section on the Site requires that you submit a password.

####  Changes to Privacy Statement

We may occasionally change our Privacy Statement. If we do, we will post the new Privacy Statement on the Site. The changes will be posted here and will take effect immediately upon posting.

Relationship Between Privacy Statement and Other Grande Communications Policies and Agreements

The policies included in this Privacy Statement are subject to the terms of any agreement, such as our Residential Agreement, you may enter into with Grande Communications and any policies we may formally transmit to our customers, such as our Subscriber Notice of Privacy Policies Under the Cable Act. In the case of a conflict between this Privacy Statement and the terms of any formal agreements or policies, the terms of the formal agreements and/or policies shall control.

## Children's Privacy Statement

Grande Communications has designed this policy in order to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ('COPPA'). This policy is intended to supplement our general Privacy Statement. If you want to read our general Privacy Statement, click here.

Although our Site is not specifically directed toward children, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from persons under the age of 13 on our Site, we recognize that parents and children visit the Site. This provides us with the opportunity to help educate consumers about the Federal Trade Commission's Children's Online Privacy Protection Rule. Please visit [www.ftc.gov/kidsprivacy](http://www.ftc.gov/kidsprivacy) for information from the Federal Trade Commission about protecting children's privacy online.

####  Policy regarding Children's Use of Site

We recommend that an adult accompany children when using content on the Site.

Grande Communications will never knowingly collect any personal information about children under the age of 13. If Grande Communications obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be deleted from our system.

Prospective users between the ages of 13 and 17 can only use the Site under their parents' or legal guardian's supervision. If you are between the ages of 13 and 17, you, your parent, or your legal guardian may request that we delete any of your personal information in our database and/or opt-out from receiving communications from us. If you wish to do so, please contact us at: [legal@grandecom.com](mailto:legal@grandecom.com).

####  Implementation of Children's Privacy Statement

A user is never required to disclose any personal information to visit the Site. Personal information is never collected from users who do not sign up for the Site or one of our services. Until registration has been completed, our system does not actually store any personal information.

Grande Communications does not substantively monitor our public areas except to determine compliance with our Appropriate Use Policy and Privacy Statement. We do not require any user to disclose personal information to use the public areas of the Site. If we obtain actual knowledge that a child under the age of 13 has disclosed personal information in a public area of our Site, we will delete any personally identifying information from the public area and from our system.

Grande Communications cannot prevent a child under the age of 13 from sending emails. However, if Grande Communications obtains actual knowledge that an email comes from a child under the age of 13, our customer service staff is trained to initiate our internal COPPA compliance process which includes the deletion from our system of all personal information about the child, including the email address. 

Grande Communications may occasionally run contests or sweepstakes. Like our general registration, sweepstakes and contests are not open to children under the age of 13. Any registration for a contest or sweepstakes likewise requests the age of the entrant. If we learn that the entrant is less than 13, the entry will be deleted. Whenever the Site requests personal information from a visitor before the visitor can participate in an activity, the visitor is not required to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in the activity.

####  Changes to Children's Privacy Statement

If Grande Communications changes its policy with respect to the collection of personal information about children under the age of 13, the changes will be posted here and will take effect immediately upon posting.

This Privacy Statement was last updated on February 5, 2008.
